{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The bacteria involved in the production of dental caries is/are", "opta": "Streptococcus mutans", "optb": "S sanguis", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Streptococcus pyogenes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following test indicates the susceptibility to streptococcal pyrogenic exotoxin?", "opta": "Schick test", "optb": "Disk test", "optc": "ASO test", "optd": "Precipitation test", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following condition is non-suppurative sequelae of Streptococcus pyogenes infections?", "opta": "Acute rheumatic fever", "optb": "Acute glomerulonephritis", "optc": "Erythema nodosum", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following cross-reacts with cell wall carbohydrate of Streptococcus pyogenes?", "opta": "Cardiac valves", "optb": "Synovial fluid", "optc": "Myocardium", "optd": "Vascular intima", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Streptococcus pyogenes can be differentiated from other haemolytic Streptococci on the basis of", "opta": "Bacitracin sensitivity", "optb": "Erythromycin sensitivity", "optc": "Aminoglycosides sensitivity", "optd": "Penicillin sensitivity", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Streptolysin O is", "opta": "antigenic", "optb": "oxygen-labile", "optc": "heat-labile", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cell wall protein of  Streptococcus pyogenes crossreacts with human", "opta": "synovial fluid", "optb": "cardiac valves", "optc": "myocardium", "optd": "vascular intima", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Individuals suffering from primary atypical pneumonia have agglutinins to", "opta": "Streptococcus MG", "optb": "S avium", "optc": "S mutans", "optd": "Enterococcus faecalis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following test(s) may establish retrospective diagnosis of streptococcal infection?", "opta": "Anti-DNase B test", "optb": "ASO test", "optc": "Streptozyme test", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacterial sore throat is caused by", "opta": "Staphylococcus aureus", "optb": "Haemophilus spp", "optc": "Streptococcus pyogenes", "optd": "Mycoplasma pneumoniae", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Crystal violet blood agar is a selective medium for", "opta": "\u03b2-haemolytic streptococci", "optb": "Staphylococcus aureus", "optc": "Corynebacterium diphtheriae", "optd": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}